JORDAN BENJAMIN

+61431916656 | jordansbenjamin@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/jordansb/ | github.com/jordansbenjamin/

SUMMARY

Emerging web developer, currently completing a full-stack web development bootcamp at Coder Academy with a diploma in IT and seeking a junior developer role for 2024. 5 years prior professional experience in the Australian Film, TV and Photography industries where I established skills in collaboration, agile problem-solving and technical expertise across diverse productions.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript/TypeScript, Python, HTML, CSS/SCSS

Technologies – React, Next.js, Node/Express, Tailwind, Bootstrap, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Flask, Prisma, Supabase **Tools** – Git, Bash, Postman, Figma, Adobe (Photoshop, Lightroom, Premiere)

EDUCATION

Academy of Interactive Technology (Coder Academy)

Diploma of Information Technology

February 2023 – December 2023

• High Distinction, WAM: 94.64

Australian Film, Television & Radio School

Bachelor of Arts, Screen Production

March 2017 - December 2020

University of Melbourne (Victorian College of The Arts)

Foundations in Film & Television

March 2016 - December 2016

PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio V2

jordansbenjamin.com

github.com/jordansbenjamin/portfolio v2

• Single Page Application developed in React and Next.js with TypeScript. Styled with Tailwind and Framer Motion.

The Cabin Company

github.com/jordansbenjamin/the-cabin-co

- Full-stack hotel management and booking system application.
- Developed in React with React Query, React Hook Form, and Supabase as the backend.
- Dashboard functionality with analytics using Recharts. Styled with React Styled Components.

Cinematica API

github.com/jordansbenjamin/Cinematica API

- Cinematica is a RESTful API developed as my third major assignment for Coder Academy allowing users to catalog, review and rate movies.
- Developed with Python and Flask with MVC architecture.
- PostgreSQL is used as the RDBMS with full CRUD functionality with authentication and authorisation.

Kazoot

github.com/jordansbenjamin/Kazoot PyProject

- Kazoot is a GUI quiz game application inspired by Kahoot! and it was intended as a study aid for a Discrete maths exam.
- Developed entirely in Python with the Tkinter model, using OOP principles.

EMPLOYMENT

Photography Assistant

Freelance

February 2021 - Present

• Worked mainly in the Australian fashion photography industry across diverse projects with brands such as Harpers Bazaar, Marie Claire, Calvin Klein, Ksubi, Scanlan Theodore, and Aje to name a few.

Studio Assistant

Studio Mondo

September 2021 – June 2022

- Managed daily studio operations and appearance. Front of house.
- Communicated with clients with booking requests and corresponding to their requirements.
- Assisted photographers with equipment set up, maintenance, troubleshooting and delivery.

Lighting Technician

Freelance

September 2020 - February 2022

• Demonstrated high levels of proficiencies in the lighting department working in the commercial space with brands such as Adobe, Virgin Airlines, Telstra, Tourism Australia, Taco Bell, Captain Morgan and Pernod Ricard to name a few.

Camera Technician

Freelance

December 2017 – September 2021

- Encompasses multiple roles within the camera department across television sets with platforms such as Netflix and Stan along with experience in diverse independent and blockbuster film productions.
- Fostered strong relationships with various film set departments, ensuring smooth operations and clear correspondence.